Kate Hevner Mueller papers, 1909-1981 C170
Indiana University Archives
- Writings, 1928-1977
  - Published Works, 1928-1977
    - Opportunities for Homemakers, 1967 (Box 10)
    - The Oregon Music Discrimination Test Various explainations, 1934 (Box 10)
    - The Other Side of the Record -Drafts, illustrations, 1969-1972 (Box 10)
    - Permanent conductors and Guest Conductors of the Major Symphony Orchestras of the U.S. 1842-1969, ca. 1969 (Box 10)
    - Poetry Attitude Test -Key, undated (Box 10)
    - Oregon Poetry Test Analysis, 1932 (Box 10)
    - Problems in the Discipline Program, 1956 (Box 10)
    - Psychological Concepts in Music -aka Psychological Experiments in Music Appreciation, 1957 (Box 10)
    - Psychological Principals in Appreciating and Promoting the Arts, undated (Box 10)
    - Psychological Principals in Art Education, 1953 (Box 10)
    - Psychological Tests in Music, 1949 (Box 10)
    - Psychophysics: The Phi Gamma Hypothesis -Draft, undated (Box 10)
    - The River Road, For Old Times Sake, Work, When Peter Came to Town, and other works, late 1910s-1920s (Box 10)
    - A Seven Decade Plan for Women's Education -Final copy, draft, 1961-1962 (Box 10)
    - Seven Phonograph Records for Testing Music Appreciation -Final copy, draft, ca. 1930s (Box 11)
    - Sex Differences in Campus Regulations, 1954 (Box 11)
    - Social-Economic Background and Campus Success -with John Mueller, 1943 (Box 11)
    - Socio-Economic Background of Women Students at IU -with John Mueller, 1949 (Box 11)
    - Some problems of Recruiting in College Personnel, 1963 (Box 11)
    - The Status of Women, 1964 (Box 11)
    - A Student Campaign against Dishonest Work on the Campus -Draft, 1953 (Box 11)
    - Student Mores on Campus, 1956 (Box 11)
    - Student Personnel Work in Higher Education (Box 11)
      - -Introduction, 1961 (Box 11)
      - -Preface draft, drafts, 1961 (Box 11)
      - -Published Hardback, 1961 (Box 11)
    - Student Personnel Work on Tomorrow's Campus, ca. 1960s (Box 11)
    - Studies in the Appreciation of Music, ca. early 1930s (Box 11)
    - Studies in Expressiveness of Music -Notes, drafts, editing, 1938 (Box 11)
    - Studies in Music Appreciation, 1956 (Box 11)
    - Study of IU Alumnae 1933-1941 -With M. Catherine Evans, 1943 (Box 11)
    - A Study of Tests for Appreciation of Music, 1931 (Box 11)
    - Tests for Esthetic Appreciation in the Field of Music, 1930 (Box 11)
    - Test for Music Discrimination, ca. early 1930s (Box 11)
    - Theory for Campus Discipline, 1958 (Box 11)
    - A Timesaving Device for the Construction of Attitude Scales -With Robert Seashore, 1933 (Box 11)
    - Three Dilemmas of the Student Personnel Profession and Their Resolution -Chapter 11, 1968 (Box 11)
    - Training for Citizenship through Student Activities, 1952 (Box 11)
    - Trends in Musical Taste -With John Mueller, 1940; 1942 (Box 11)
    - Twenty-five Years in the IU Auditorium: the Convocations -drafts, Published Article, 1966 (Box 11)
    - Twenty-Seven Major American Symphony Orchestras: A History and Analysis of Their Repertoires 1842-1843 through 1969-1970 (Box 11)
      - -title, 1973 (Box 11)
      - -Typed Draft, ca. 1972 (Box 11)
      - -manuscript, Part I, ca. 1972 (Box 11)
      - -drafts, ca. 1972 (Box 11)
      - -various drafts, ca. 1972 (Box 11)
      - -published volume, 1973 (Box 11)
    - A Wise Son Maketh a Glad Father, undated (Box 11)
    - Women's Education- For What?, 1955 (Box 11)
    - Women's Education: Vocational or Liberal Emphasis?, ca. 1950s-1960s (Box 11)
    - The Women's Liberation Movement: What Delayed Its Impact?, 1977 (Box 11)
    - Work and Study Programs for the Homemaker, undated (Box 11)
    - Your Share in Vocational Guidance for 1949, 1948 (Box 11)
  - Other writings and books, 1930-1966
    - Bibliography, ca. late 1930s; 1960s (Box 11)
    - Other Writings, 1964; 1972 (Box 11)
    - Unidentified Drafts, ca. 1930s-1950s (Box 11)
    - Visual Outline of Psychology (Box 11)
      - 1935 (Box 11)
    - New Horizons for College Women "What Its All About" (Box 11)
      - 1960 (Box 11)
    - The Challenge to Women "Education: The Realistic Approach", 1966 (Box 11)
    - Social Deviancy Among Youth "Programs for Deviant Girls", 1966 (Box 11)
    - Counseling Techniques for Mature Women, 1966 (Box 11)
- Miscellaneous materials (Box 12)
  Scope and Contents
  Contains microfilm, photostats of 19th c. Philharmonica concerts, "Speak-o-Phone" records, and record albums.